YOGESH ARORA

GURGAON,HARYANA (INDIA) +919911894889 YOGESH190192@GMAIL.COM

SUMMARY:

Around 3 years of IT experience in software analysis, development and implementation, and extensive experience in SAP ABAP Implementation, Roll-out, and Production Support, having detailed technical expertise on SAP HR, PM, FI/CO, SD and SRM. Experience in developing objects using Object Oriented Programming. Developed global/local classes and enhanced standard with methods as per the requirements (Object Oriented ABAP).

SKILLS:

- SAP R/3, ECC 6.0, SRM 5.0, CRM 7.0.
- SAP Modules: HR, SD, PM, CRM, FI/CO, BI, SRM.
- SAP Skills: ABAP Webdynpro, BADI, User-Exit, Adobe Forms, RICEFW, Web Services, ALV, ABAP Objects, HR Infotypes, Web UI MVC Architecture.
- Cross Applications: ALE, IDOC, RFC, BAPI.
- User Interface: Menu Painter, Screen Painter, Module Pool Programming, ALV Grid.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES LTD.

SAP ABAP DEVELOPER, March 2018 - Present

Client: Punjab National Bank (08/2020 - Current)

Project: CRM Implementation / Support

- Worked On Change Request of revamping existing lead management system post amalgamation of OBC and UTI bank to streamline processes.
- Experience in SAP CRM ABAP and expertise in CRM Web Client UI BADI, CRM EVENTS, WEBUI.
- Good Understanding of Web UI MVC Architecture and CRM One order framework. Experience in Enhancements of CRM applications using EEWB and AET.
- Good Working experience in ECC and integration between CRM and ECC.

Client: Powergrid Corporation Of India Ltd. (05/2018 - 07/2020)

Project: ERP Implementation / Support

- Developed ALV reports with Web Dynpro and developed Web Dynpro applications with view, windows and configured outbound, inbound plugs and bind them with navigation links.
- Developed Transfer Order process in HR Module.
- Developed Insurance Process in PM Module for first level inspection by the required insurance company when the plant/sub plant fails.

- Documenting the business requirements and providing solutions in SAP to the customer requirements.
- Developed award report through web dynpro in SRM for vendors of powergrid.
- Designing and development of RICEFW objects, formulating unit test plans for RICEFW objects and deployment of solutions.
- Worked on Adobe forms in HR, SD, FI/CO Module.

EDUCATION:

- THAPAR UNIVERSITY, PATIALA
 Master In Computer Application (MCA) [2014 2017] with 8.2 CGPA
- AMITY UNIVERSITY, GURGAON
 Bachelor In Computer Application (BCA) [2011 2014] with 7.9 CGPA
- S.N.S.P.S, GURGAON CLASS X11 (Commerce) [2010 – 2011] with 80.5 percentage
- LIONS PUBLIC SCHOOL, GURGAON CLASS X [2008 – 2009] with 72 percentage

Achievements / Awards:

- Applause Award for Insurance Process solution in SAP PM Module (08/2018).
- Star of the month award (09/2019).

Additional Skills:

Bilingual in French and English.